♪With a long sword and a large bow♪
♪장검과 큰 활을 들고♪
♪I took over Gangdong♪
♪강동은 내가 차지했다♪
♪It’s crowded with a lot of people♪
♪사람이 많아 붐비네요♪
Here we go again!
또 가자!
(Doohyeon government office)
(두현청)
=Prosperous Underground= =Episode 11=
=번성하는 지하= =제11화=
Outside the south gate, an old temple hidden in the forest
남문밖 숲 속에 숨겨진 오래된 사찰
The criminal is about to commit another crime.
범인은 또 다른 범죄를 저지르려고 합니다.
Go right away
지금 당장 가세요
It seems that the criminal sent it again.
범인이 다시 보낸 것 같습니다.
The criminal is trying to use us again to catch people.
범인은 사람을 잡기 위해 다시 우리를 이용하려고 합니다 .
But the problem is that I don't know who I'm trying to catch this time.
그런데 문제는 이번에는 누구를 잡으려는 것인지 알 수 없다는 점이다.
We do this every time
우리는 매번 이렇게 해요
Should I do what he says?
그가 말한 대로 해야 할까요?
The culprit is us
범인은 우리야
I would have guessed that there was no clue.
나는 단서가 없다고 추측했을 것입니다.
Even though I know I'm being used
내가 이용당하고 있다는 걸 알면서도
I have no choice but to chase after it
쫓아갈 수밖에 없어
Moreover, Hyeonryeong Nari also
게다가 현령나리도
They told us to go, so we should go.
그들이 우리에게 가라고 했으니 우리도 가야 합니다.
(Ak's Bansinseon)
(Ak의 반신선)
wake up and see
일어나서 보아라
I will take care of your life and your future.
나는 당신의 삶과 미래를 돌볼 것입니다.
You...
너...
It's me
나야
Don’t you already know it’s me?
나인 줄 이미 알고 있지 않니?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
What is that beard again?
저 수염은 또 뭐야?
Didn't you have a beard before?
예전에는 수염이 없었나요?
The beard is attached
수염이 붙어있어요
Take it off to check.
확인을 위해 벗어보세요.
How come you haven't been here for so long?
왜 이렇게 오랫동안 여기에 안 오셨나요?
20 years have passed
20년이 지났다
Our appearance would have changed a lot too.
우리의 모습도 많이 변했을 거예요.
How did I find out?
내가 어떻게 알아냈나요?
You know it when you see the naked eyebrows of your hometown
고향의 벗은 눈썹을 보면 알잖아
Did you find out just by looking at that?
그거 보고 딱 알았어요?
Actually, I wasn't sure either.
사실 나도 확신이 없었다.
But I didn't even try
하지만 난 시도조차 하지 않았어
How can I solve my problem?
내 문제를 어떻게 해결할 수 있나요?
For what reason did I come looking for you?
내가 무슨 이유로 당신을 찾으러 왔나요?
first of all
가장 먼저
I called you to make sure it was you.
당신이 맞는지 확인하려고 전화했어요.
and
그리고
I called you here to resolve the issue.
문제를 해결하기 위해 여기로 전화했습니다.
Aren't you trying to exchange my life for money?
내 인생을 돈으로 바꾸려는 건 아니지?
Did you get caught?
잡혔나요?
If so, how much will you give me?
그렇다면 얼마를 주실 건가요?
Why should I give you money?
내가 왜 너한테 돈을 줘야 하는데?
I have to pay hush money
조용히 돈을 내야 해
If you don't pay
지불하지 않으면
Because I will spread the word
내가 소문을 퍼뜨릴 테니까
What good is spreading rumors?
소문을 퍼뜨리면 무슨 소용이 있나요?
Everyone thinks you're crazy
다들 당신이 미쳤다고 생각해요
Otherwise, I'll tell that crazy genius.
그렇지 않으면 그 미친 천재에게 말하겠지.
He promised to give me a thousand pieces of silver.
그는 나에게 은화 천 개를 주겠다고 약속했습니다.
If you are him
당신이 그 사람이라면
Would you believe it?
믿으시겠습니까?
Aren't you afraid of me?
당신은 나를 두려워하지 않습니까?
Shouldn't you be afraid of me?
나를 두려워해야 하지 않나요?
lately
최근에
Haven't you heard that there was a murder in the castle ?
성에서 살인사건이 일어났다는 소식을 못 들으셨나요 ?
You killed them all?
당신이 그 사람들을 다 죽였나요?
No way
안 돼요
I don't believe it
나는 그것을 믿지 않는다
Of course me too
물론 나도
20 years ago
20 년 전에
what happened
무슨 일이에요
where were you
당신은 어디에 있었나요?
I don't know why they changed their name
왜 이름을 바꿨는지는 모르겠지만
Sore
아픈
You couldn't have killed someone.
당신은 누군가를 죽일 수 없었습니다.
never
절대
Are you so sure?
정말 확신하시나요?
of course
물론
Have you forgotten that I know how to use physiognomy?
내가 관상학을 사용하는 방법을 알고 있다는 것을 잊었습니까?
Besides, aren’t we friends?
게다가 우리는 친구 아닌가?
Friends?
친구?
father
아버지
but
하지만
We are friends
우리는 친구 다
Then you are a friend
그럼 당신은 친구입니다
I'll show you how to betray me
나를 배신하는 방법을 보여줄게
How can you tell me how to betray you ?
당신을 배신하는 방법을 어떻게 말해줄 수 있나요?
I feel so sorry for you
너한테 너무 미안해
You're trying to help.
당신은 도우려고 노력하고 있습니다.
Do you know any giants?
거인을 아시나요?
(Ak's Bansinseon)
(Ak의 반신선)
Looks like that fortune teller is waiting for a friend again.
저 점쟁이가 또 친구를 기다리고 있는 것 같군요.
Maybe catch that person’s friend today?
오늘 그 사람의 친구를 잡을 수 있을까요?
someone came
누군가 왔어
That person's friend is Deacon Jang of the Seol family?
그 사람 친구가 설씨 장집사라고요?
Doesn't that make sense?
말이 안 되나요?
Who are you?
누구세요?
bump
충돌
Are you a bad teacher?
당신은 나쁜 선생님입니까?
Are you a giant?
당신은 거인입니까?
I am the butler of the giant's mansion.
나는 거인의 저택의 집사이다.
Although you did not come
비록 당신은 오지 않았지만
I brought you gold
내가 금을 가져왔어
Well, I'll have to check it out.
글쎄요, 확인해 봐야겠네요.
Anyway
그래도
You will never fool me.
당신은 결코 나를 속일 수 없습니다.
I too was once a master.
나 역시 한때는 주인이었다.
I've seen gold
나는 금을 본 적이 있어요
tell me
말해 주세요
what do you know
당신은 무엇을 알 수 있습니까
What are those people doing?
그 사람들은 무엇을 하고 있나요?
Looks like a gold bar?
금괴처럼 보이죠?
The fortune telling teacher uses information from friends.
운세 선생님은 친구들의 정보를 활용합니다.
I'm thinking of selling it to the giant.
거인에게 팔까 생각 중이에요.
Let's go
갑시다
What are you doing now?
뭐하세요?
The information you want is hidden in the donkey's body.
당신이 원하는 정보는 당나귀의 몸 속에 숨겨져 있습니다.
I wrote it down on a piece of paper under the saddle
안장 밑에 종이에 적어놨어요
Quickly chase after me
빨리 나를 쫓아와
I don't think so.
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않습니다.
While I was chasing the donkey
내가 당나귀를 쫓고 있는 동안
You're going to run away with the gold.
당신은 금을 가지고 도망칠 것입니다.
When I get the information
정보를 얻었을 때
I'm afraid it will work against you.
나는 그것이 당신에게 불리하게 작용할까봐 두렵습니다.
How come you're still not chasing me?
왜 아직도 나를 쫓지 않는 거죠?
How come you don't run away?
왜 도망치지 않는 거야?
The criminal told us to catch Deacon Jang.
범인은 장집사를 잡으라고 했습니다.
Why would I chase a donkey?
내가 왜 당나귀를 쫓겠는가?
You must be slower than a donkey.
당나귀보다 느려야 합니다.
tell me
말해 주세요
what you know
당신이 알고
tell me everything
나에게 모든 것을 말해주세요
catch it
그것을 잡아
don't come close
가까이 오지 마
Because if he comes, I'll kill this guy.
그 사람이 오면 내가 그 사람을 죽일 테니까.
Is it important to catch the criminal?
범인을 잡는 것이 중요합니까?
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
Scatter up and follow them!
흩어져서 따라가세요!
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
it's okay
괜찮아요
It's just lime
그냥 라임이에요
The commendation he used was made of ceramics.
그가 사용한 표창장은 도자기로 만들어졌다.
ceramic?
세라믹?
Inside the hollow ceramic commendation
중공 세라믹 표창장 내부
They added lime.
그들은 석회를 추가했습니다.
Sore
아픈
It didn't seem like they were trying to take our lives .
그들이 우리의 목숨을 앗아가려는 것 같지는 않았습니다.
The injuries our children suffered
우리 아이들이 입은 상처
Not all injuries were fatal
모든 부상이 치명적인 것은 아니었습니다.
What happened to that fortune telling teacher?
그 점술 선생님은 어떻게 됐나요?
I took advantage of the confusion and ran away.
나는 혼란을 이용하여 도망쳤다.
Even though we searched the area for half a day,
반나절 동안 그 지역을 수색했는데도
Couldn't find it
찾을 수 없습니다
It looks like the culprit
범인같네요
This time, the person who told us to catch him
이번엔 잡아오라고 한 사람이
I don't think it's him
내 생각엔 그 사람이 아닌 것 같아
The letter he sent last time was
그가 지난번에 보낸 편지는 다음과 같다.
Tell us to catch our bullies
우리 괴롭히는 놈들 잡으라고 말해
If it meant confining me to a castle,
나를 성에 가두는 것이라면,
Maybe this time
아마도 이번에는
It probably means that we should catch Deacon Jang.
아마도 장집사를 잡아야 한다는 뜻일 것이다.
He creates opportunities
그는 기회를 창조한다
I'm thinking of killing Jang Gye-jo.
장계조를 죽일 생각도 있다.
Is the government trying to use a spy?
정부가 스파이를 이용하려고 하는 걸까요?
That's probably not it
그건 아마 아닐 거야
First of all , there are a lot of people in government offices, so it is easy to make mistakes.
우선, 관공서에는 사람이 많아서 실수를 하기 쉽습니다.
also
또한
Even if it kills me
나를 죽이더라도
whatever he wants
그가 원하는 것은 무엇이든
'Cause you can't hang up the body
왜냐면 몸을 매달 수 없으니까
So how can this be an opportunity?
그렇다면 이것이 어떻게 기회가 될 수 있습니까?
It's an opportunity, because Jang Gye-jo has become a loner.
장계조가 외톨이가 되었기 때문에 기회다.
Because you tried to use me
네가 나를 이용하려 했기 때문에
Let's talk again then
그럼 다시 얘기하자
i really
나는 정말
'Cause no one knows if they'll help him
왜냐면 그들이 그를 도와줄지는 아무도 모르거든
Seol Hyo-ryeom
설효렴
The wise man, Nari, is unwell.
현자 나리가 몸이 좋지 않습니다.
I will take your place
내가 네 자리를 대신할게
Please tell me I ask for your understanding.
말씀해 주시기 바라며, 양해 부탁드립니다.
no
아니요
Just because Warrior Song himself came
송무사님이 직접 오셨다고 해서
It's like saving my face.
그것은 내 얼굴을 구하는 것과 같습니다.
Well, today
글쎄, 오늘은
What brought you here?
무엇이 당신을 여기로 데려왔나요?
I will tell you bluntly.
솔직하게 말씀드리겠습니다.
yesternight
간밤
They say the government office caught my butler, Jang Gye-jo .
관공서가 집사 장계조를 붙잡았다고 합니다.
What crime did he commit?
그는 어떤 범죄를 저질렀나요?
I tried to harm someone with a sword.
나는 칼로 누군가를 해치려고 했습니다.
To whom?
누구에게?
The fortune telling teacher is evil Cheolchwi.
점술선생님은 사악한 철취입니다.
Is the fisherman dead or injured?
어부가 죽거나 다쳤나요?
Fortunately, the police arrived on time.
다행히 경찰이 정시에 도착했습니다.
I stopped Jang Gye-jo from harming people.
장계조가 사람을 해치는 것을 막았습니다.
That means you're safe.
그것은 당신이 안전하다는 것을 의미합니다.
But you hurt two of my police officers with a knife.
그런데 당신은 내 경찰 두 명을 칼로 다쳤어요.
His gang injured three people with throwing stars.
그의 갱단은 표창으로 ​​세 명을 다쳤습니다.
That is, five people working at the government office
즉, 관공서에 근무하는 5명이
You're saying you got hurt because of our butler.
우리 집사 때문에 상처받았다고 하던데.
Otherwise, I spent my silver money.
그렇지 않으면 은화를 썼습니다.
I guess I should give it as a consolation prize.
위로의 상으로 드려야 할 것 같습니다.
I
나
Instead, thank you
대신, 감사합니다.
This incident is not serious either.
이번 사건도 심각하지 않다.
pay a deposit
보증금을 지불하다
I want to save the butler.
집사를 구하고 싶어요.
When you review the case
사건을 검토해보면
Come to my house and tell him
우리 집에 와서 그 사람에게 말해요
I guarantee it
나는 그것을 보증한다
I will definitely run when you call me
네가 부르면 반드시 달려갈게
Warrior Song
전사의 노래
Can you do me a favor?
부탁 하나만 들어줄 수 있나요?
What did Jang Gye-jo do last night?
장계조는 어젯밤에 무엇을 했나요?
It's related to a serial murder case.
연쇄살인사건과 관련이 있습니다.
Moreover, he threatened Ak Cheolchwi with a sword.
게다가 악철취에게 칼을 휘둘러 위협했다.
The police saw it clearly.
경찰은 그것을 분명히 보았습니다.
Moreover, he disobeyed arrest and injured government officials.
더욱이 그는 체포에 불복종하고 정부 관리들에게 부상을 입혔습니다.
Isn’t everything a serious sin?
모든 것이 심각한 죄가 아닌가?
I'm going to invade your mansion
난 네 저택을 침공할 거야
Just because I didn't catch his gang
내가 그 놈의 패거리를 잡지 못했다는 이유만으로
I think I was kind to you.
나는 당신에게 친절했다고 생각합니다.
get a guarantee
보증을 받다
Postponing the interrogation
심문을 연기하다
A warrior like me
나 같은 전사
I don't think it's up to you to decide.
나는 결정하는 것이 당신에게 달려 있다고 생각하지 않습니다.
what
무엇
If you really want to
정말로 원한다면
I'll just go now
이제 그냥 갈게요
I'm busy with official duties
나는 공식적인 업무로 바쁘다
Please understand that I cannot see you off far away.
멀리서 배웅할 수 없는 점 양해 부탁드립니다.
Warrior Song
전사의 노래
When the prefectural government deliberates on the agenda
현 정부가 안건을 심의하는 경우
I will also leave that place.
나도 그 자리를 떠날 것이다.
If there is evidence and a complainant,
증거가 있고 고소인이 있는 경우
Execute the sentence on the spot
그 자리에서 문장을 실행해 보세요.
Even if you beat Jang Gye-jo to death
장계조를 때려죽여도
I won't have anything to say
난 할말이 없을거야
However, even the county commander, Nari, did not go to war.
그러나 군수 나리조차 전쟁에 참여하지 않았다.
If you personally execute a sentence and torture it to obtain a confession,
자백을 얻기 위해 직접 형을 집행하고 고문을 한다면 ,
I will never be able to follow
난 절대로 따라갈 수 없을 거야
me too
저도요
There is a fountain like that
저런 분수도 있구나
song warrior
노래 전사
Now that things have come to this, let's release it.
이제 상황이 이렇기 때문에 릴리스해 보겠습니다.
Do you really want to release me?
정말로 나를 풀어주고 싶나요?
I heard it all from behind the folding screen
병풍 뒤에서 다 들었어
Isn’t that guy right?
그 사람 맞지 않아요?
There is no accuser and no testimony.
고소인도 없고 증언도 없습니다.
What should I do with the trial?
재판은 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Let go
가자
All right
괜찮은
I'll release it today
오늘 공개할게요
Samgyeong-ah
삼경아
I caught the donkey
당나귀를 잡았어요
Did I tell you? We have to spread out and search
내가 말했었나요? 널리 퍼져서 수색해야 해
how is it?
어때요?
No?
아니요?
doesn't exist
존재하지 않는다
That fortune telling teacher is so cunning.
그 점술 선생님은 정말 교활해요.
What about the donkey?
당나귀는 어떻습니까?
Let's take him to the government office.
그를 관공서로 데려가자.
Is it physical evidence?
물적 증거인가요?
Warrior Song
전사의 노래
What do you want me to say?
당신은 내가하고 싶은 말이?
For what reason did you threaten Akcheolchwi with a sword?
악철취를 칼로 위협한 이유는 무엇인가?
I was just kidding.
농담이에요.
If you don't believe it, come find him
믿기지 않는다면 그 사람을 찾아오세요
Shouldn't you just ask?
그냥 물어보면 안되는 걸까요?
You really like pranks.
당신은 장난을 정말 좋아해요.
noha
하지만
a few days ago
며칠 전
We discussed punishment, right?
우리는 처벌에 대해 논의했습니다. 그렇죠?
The punishment of lightning in Gyeongseong
경성에서 번개의 형벌
I heard it’s very different from a government office?
관공서하고는 많이 다르다고 들었는데?
yes
예
Even if you just look at the three fires,
불 세개만 봐도
Everyone had different opinions.
모두가 다른 의견을 가지고있었습니다.
Which is scarier?
어느 것이 더 무서운가요?
When a small person sees
작은 사람이 보면
I think the government office is scarier.
관공서가 더 무서운 것 같아요.
I heard it's not like that for everyone?
다들 그렇지 않다고 들었는데?
when i see
내가 볼때
It seems like the punishment of Gyeongseong Cheonrae is more scary.
경성천래의 처벌이 더 무서운 것 같습니다.
Little people have different opinions
작은 사람들은 서로 다른 의견을 가지고 있습니다
If so, we
그렇다면 우리는
How about trying it with Deacon Jang?
장집사님과 함께 해보시는 건 어떨까요?
Isn't that... a bit odd?
그거... 좀 이상하지 않나요?
Is this a joke?
지금 농담하는 거지?
lily
백합
Let's do a favor.
부탁 좀 하자.
Could you please send a message to the Seol Giant ?
설자이언트에게 메시지를 보내주실 수 있나요 ?
Since I came out
나왔을 때부터
Come pick me up
나 데리러 와줘
My family's elders will give me a big reward.
우리 집 어른들이 나에게 큰 상을 주실 것이다.
Can not be done
할 수 없습니다
Warrior Song gave a solemn warning.
송무사는 엄숙한 경고를 했습니다.
They said I had to go back alone.
혼자 돌아가야 한다고 하더군요.
You can never send a message
절대로 메시지를 보낼 수 없습니다.
Think of it as exercise
운동이라고 생각하세요
The culprit is said to be a giant who will come to bail the person out.
범인은 사람을 구제하러 올 거인이라고 한다.
Because I can’t keep Jang Gye-jo locked up.
장계조를 가둬둘 수는 없으니까.
He must have known that he would definitely be released.
그는 자신이 반드시 석방될 것이라는 것을 알고 있었을 것입니다.
So on the way
그래서 가는 길에
They must have kidnapped Jang Gye-jo.
장계조를 납치한 게 틀림없어요.
Otherwise, send agile police officers to follow behind.
그렇지 않으면 민첩한 경찰을 보내 뒤를 따르십시오.
How about taking the opportunity to catch the culprit?
범인을 잡을 기회를 가져보는 것은 어떨까요?
It doesn't work
작동하지 않습니다
don't forget
잊지 마세요
To the government office
관공서로
There is someone who knows the culprit
범인을 아는 사람이 있다
Besides, the criminal is quick-witted.
게다가 범인은 눈치도 빠르다.
If there are a lot of people
사람이 많으면
You will definitely notice
당신은 분명히 알아 차릴 것입니다
All right
괜찮은
Otherwise, I will follow alone.
그렇지 않으면 나 혼자 따라갈 것이다.
Are you hurt?
상처받았나요?
I wasn't hurt
난 상처받지 않았어
You couldn't even hit me
넌 날 때릴 수도 없었지
I am...
그래요...
Just because I was surprised
그냥 놀랐으니까
I just fell off the roof
방금 지붕에서 떨어졌어요
As expected, I got hit again
예상대로 또 당했어
Even see through my ruse
내 계략도 꿰뚫어보네
Counterattacking?
반격?
I got rid of Jang Gye-jo's martial arts for no reason.
장계조 무술을 괜히 없앴습니다.
I can't even serve people.
나는 사람들에게 봉사할 수도 없습니다.
How can you serve a ghost?
어떻게 유령을 섬길 수 있나요?
Three Views
세 가지 견해
What does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
(How can you serve a ghost?) The culprit is Jang Gye-jo
(귀신을 어떻게 섬길 수 있는가?) 범인은 장계조
Or that Jang-gwi at that time
아니면 그때 그 장귀가
The master who served
섬기던 주인
I want to say it's a demon
악마라고 말하고 싶다
Brother Death Gun
형제 죽음의 총
Brother Samkyung tricked Brother Death Gun.
삼경 형제는 사총 형제를 속였습니다.
How can you say Samgyeong deceived me?
어떻게 삼경이가 나를 속였다고 할 수 있나요?
The information that the fortune telling teacher hid in the donkey’s body
점술 선생님이 당나귀 몸에 숨겨둔 정보
The mutt probably already got it
그 똥개는 아마도 이미 그것을 얻었을 것입니다
Samgyeong brother used to be
삼경오빠는 예전에
Every day, I came to my house to chop firewood and draw water.
매일 집에 와서 장작을 패고 물을 길었습니다.
These days, my face hasn't even been shown.
요즘은 얼굴도 안 나오더라구요.
He must be hiding something.
그 사람 뭔가 숨기고 있는 게 틀림없어요.
Although I speak less these days
요즘 말은 덜 하지만
What is the reason for deceiving us?
우리를 속이는 이유가 무엇입니까?
If, as the fortune telling teacher says,
운세 선생님이 말씀하신 대로
If there was anyone who survived the fire at that time
당시 화재에서 살아남은 사람이 있었다면
That person
저 사람
Must be the culprit
범인임에 틀림없어
Do you need to hide it?
굳이 숨길 필요가 있나요?
I just need to fix it
그냥 고쳐야지
If so, that person
그렇다면 그 사람은
What if it’s someone you can’t catch?
잡을 수 없는 사람이라면?
We can't catch it?
우리는 그것을 잡을 수 없습니다?
If so, that person
그렇다면 그 사람은
What if it's a Song warrior?
송전사라면 어떨까요?
That can't be possible
그건 불가능해요
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
What is the reason for doing it?
그렇게 하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
I said I saw the document.
나는 그 문서를 보았다고 말했다.
You said there was a master in the Yuk family, right?
육가에 사부가 있다고 했죠?
Yeah, it's bad luck
응, 불운이야
But they said he died in a fire.
그런데 화재로 사망했다고 하네요.
It must have been burned so its original appearance could not be found at all.
아마도 불에 타서 원래의 모습을 전혀 찾을 수 없을 것입니다.
How would we know who it was?
그게 누구인지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
furthermore
뿐만 아니라
If that person is alive
그 사람이 살아있다면
Isn’t he similar in age to Warrior Song?
송무사와 나이가 비슷하지 않나요?
He said the guy was lame.
그 사람은 절름발이였다고 하더군요.
How can a cripple kill someone?
불구자가 어떻게 사람을 죽일 수 있습니까?
You can pretend to be lame
못난 척해도 돼
Even murder can have an accomplice.
살인에도 공범이 있을 수 있다.
Brother Bong
봉 형제
Are you really doubting Warrior Song?
정말 전사 노래를 의심하고 있습니까?
It's just a metaphor
그건 단지 비유일 뿐이야
But...
하지만...
But someone
그런데 누군가
You know our every move.
당신은 우리의 모든 움직임을 알고 있습니다.
For example, Song warrior
예를 들어 송 전사
The mutt is trying to stop the song from flowing into the warrior's ears.
똥개는 노래가 전사의 귀로 흘러 들어가는 것을 막으려고 노력하고 있습니다.
Lim Hunting was also killed.
임 헌팅도 사망했습니다.
Samgyeong brother
삼경오빠
I don't want us to be hunted down
나는 우리가 쫓기는 것을 원하지 않는다
I must have hidden it.
나는 그것을 숨겼음에 틀림없다.
What on earth are you trying to do?
도대체 무엇을 하려는 걸까요?
The mutt is probably
똥개는 아마도
You're taking risks alone.
당신은 혼자 위험을 감수하고 있습니다.
(energy)
(에너지)
(Master)
(주인)
(You said it's a long way to achieve justice, right?)
(정의를 이루려면 갈길이 멀다고 하셨죠?)
(I finally found out about it)
(드디어 알게 됐어요)
(Justice is not a long way away)
(정의는 멀지 않다)
(Justice achieved)
(정의가 실현됨)
(government office)
(정부청사)
(There are several paths)
(여러 가지 경로가 있습니다)
mutt
바보
country chicken
컨트리 치킨
What's going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Well, just
글쎄, 그냥
snow giant
눈의 거인
To see if they will buy my painting
그들이 내 그림을 살 것인지 알아보기 위해
Aren't you going in?
안 들어가요?
Are you following my footsteps?
당신은 내 발자취를 따르고 있습니까?
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
It's only one test
시험은 딱 하나야
How did you know I was here?
내가 여기 있다는 걸 어떻게 알았나요?
Are you trying to join hands with the snow giant?
눈의 거인과 손을 잡으려고 하시나요?
I have no other way
나에겐 다른 방법이 없어
that person is a bad person
그 사람은 나쁜 사람이야
A person who has committed all kinds of evil deeds.
온갖 악행을 저지른 사람입니다.
Are you doing this knowing that?
그걸 알면서 이러는 거야?
you are a police officer
당신은 경찰입니다
I did everything a police officer should do.
나는 경찰이 해야 할 일을 다 했다.
So now
그래서 지금
To do something I shouldn't do
하지 말아야 할 일을 하려고
After Master passed away
스승님이 돌아가신 후
you changed
당신은 변 했어요
In the past
과거에
Because he’s a mutt with a tight front and back
앞뒤가 꽉 막힌 똥개이기 때문에
If you're upset, run and bite
심심하면 달려가서 물어뜯어라
You used to bark
넌 짖곤 했지
that
저것
It's because I had a back in the past.
과거에 등이 있었기 때문입니다.
You are starting to resemble your teacher more and more now.
당신은 이제 점점 선생님을 닮아가기 시작했습니다.
If Master knows
마스터가 알면
I don't know if you'll be happy
당신이 행복할지 모르겠어요
I can't let you in
나는 당신을 들여 보낼 수 없습니다
country chicken
컨트리 치킨
I don't want to argue with you
나는 당신과 논쟁하고 싶지 않습니다
If you interfere
방해하면
Grab you first
먼저 너를 잡아라
I'll lock you in the government office for half a day.
반나절 동안 관공서에 가두겠습니다.
And then I'll do my thing
그럼 난 내 할 일을 할게
You killed Lim Hunting, right?
당신이 림 헌팅을 죽였죠?
Why would I kill Lim Hunting?
내가 왜 림 헌팅을 죽여야 하는가?
Rather than asking the reason
이유를 묻는 것보다
How can a single Bae-dong
어떻게 배동 하나가
Inheriting such a big business
이렇게 큰 사업을 물려받다
suddenly
갑자기
We have to ask whether he has become a giant.
그가 거인이 되었는지 물어봐야 한다.
Are you talking about me?
너 나에 대해 말하는 거니?
20 years ago, the Yuk family disappeared due to a fire.
20년 전, 화재로 육씨 일가가 실종됐다.
After that, the Yuk family's gold and silver treasures and
그 후 육씨 가문의 금은보화와
affiliated store
가맹점
And to the mansion
그리고 저택으로
Who took over?
누가 인수했나요?
don't ask me that
나한테 그런 건 묻지 마
I'll have to look for it at the government office.
관공서에서 찾아봐야겠네요.
Not in the government office
관공서에는 없고
It's there somewhere else
거기 다른 곳에 있어요
looking at me
나를 바라보며
I'm so clumsy
난 너무 서툴러
The store's sign and name are
가게의 간판과 이름은
can change
바꿀 수있다
worker, owner
노동자, 주인
Even accounting teachers can change, but
회계교사도 바뀔 수 있지만
Transaction details of the payment store
결제가맹점의 거래내역
Few people can change
변할 수 있는 사람은 거의 없다
I only went to 3 payment stores.
저는 결제 매장 3곳만 가봤습니다.
There are a dozen store owners.
상점 주인이 십여 명이 있습니다.
The previous owner was Yuk Won-pok.
전 주인은 육원복씨였다.
After Yuk Won-pok died, Yuk Geun-shin
육원복이 죽은 뒤 육근신이
After a fire broke out in the Yuk family
Yuk 가족에 화재가 발생한 후
I held the sixth position for three years.
나는 3년 동안 6위 자리를 유지했습니다.
Those three years
그 3년
Yukjik is not Duhyeon
육직은 두현이 아니다
It was at Jonghyun.
종현이였어요.
In the ledger every time
매번 장부에
It had the seal of Jonghyun’s store on it.
종현 가게의 인장이 찍혀 있었습니다.
Well, what will happen three years later?
그렇다면 3년 후에는 어떻게 될까요?
They all changed to Seol’s last name.
모두 설씨 성으로 바뀌었다.
Even if I took control of the Yuk family store,
육패밀리스토어를 장악했다고 해도
What's the problem?
뭐가 문제 야?
Doesn’t Seol Giant not only have the Yuk family’s store ?
설자이언트가 육가네 가게만 있는거 아닌가요 ?
He is also the owner of Chuhwaru.
추화루의 주인이기도 하다.
I don't have many stores
매장이 많이 없어요
King Muryujae’s teacher
무류재왕의 스승
Good at calligraphy and seal engraving
서예와 전각을 잘한다.
I heard it from my nephew
조카한테 들었는데
He said he could imitate many different handwritings.
그는 다양한 손글씨를 흉내낼 수 있다고 말했습니다.
Representative Jeong of the name
이름의 정 대표
I was always looking after the sick of the six atomic bombs.
나는 항상 6개의 원자폭탄의 병자를 돌보고 있었습니다.
you
너
Forging a will or document
유언장이나 문서를 위조하는 행위
He poisoned Yuk Won Bomb.
그는 육원폭탄을 독살했다.
Set a fire and kill the Yuk family.
불을 지르고 Yuk 가족을 죽여라.
I felt like that property had been taken away.
나는 그 재산을 빼앗긴 것 같은 느낌이 들었습니다.
Isn’t that a deadly sin?
그거 치명적인 죄 아닌가요?
To commit such a crime
이런 범죄를 저지르려면
There must also be an accomplice.
공범도 있어야 합니다.
Even in government offices
관공서에서도
Shouldn't there be an accomplice?
공범이 있어야 하지 않겠습니까?
That person
저 사람
I don't know if I found it
찾았는지 모르겠네요
He was my teacher.
그는 나의 선생님이었습니다.
Your teacher?
너의 선생님?
They put a condition on giving Lim Hunting freedom.
그들은 임헌팅에게 자유를 주는 조건을 걸었다.
Conciliate my teacher
선생님을 화해시키세요
Master told me to stop the fire.
스승님이 나에게 불을 끄라고 말씀하셨어요.
It's not enough to have them determine that the accident was caused by a flammable substance.
사고가 인화성 물질에 의해 발생했다고 판단하는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
Also, the documents of the government office
또한, 관공서의 서류
Didn’t you let them handle it?
그들이 처리하도록 두지 않았나요?
After your master died
네 주인이 죽은 후에
That fact
그 사실
I wonder if Lim Hunting knows too
임헌팅도 알고 있을지 궁금해
me again
나 또
By means of serial murder
연쇄살인을 통해
Imhunting is also killed
임헌팅도 죽는다
Prevent secrets from being revealed
비밀이 공개되는 것을 방지하세요
Is this what you mean?
너가 말하는게 이거니?
You can't manage it.
당신은 그것을 관리할 수 없습니다.
A storyteller suits you
스토리텔러가 당신에게 어울린다
The story we have just put together
우리가 방금 정리한 이야기
If you did it at a tea shop, you would have won quite a few awards.
찻집에서 했다면 꽤 많은 상을 받았을 겁니다.
But are you going to catch me?
그런데 나를 잡을 건가요?
Aside from catching me
나를 잡는 것 외에도
Just this action today
오늘은 이 동작만
I will have the government strip you of your position.
나는 정부가 당신의 직위를 박탈하도록 할 것입니다.
I can make you hit 10 sticks.
막대기 10개를 치게 만들 수 있어요.
six jobs
여섯 가지 직업
There's something you need to know
당신이 알아야 할 것이 있습니다
Today I didn't come to ask for your sins
오늘 나는 너희 죄를 묻러 온 것이 아니다
just
단지
I'm here to make a deal
나는 거래를 하러 왔습니다
madam
부인
Are you a stepchild?
당신은 의붓자식입니까?
yes, it's me
응, 나야
I came to look for my brother Samgyeong.
삼경오빠를 찾으러 왔습니다.
Samgyeong went to the government office.
삼경이 관공서에 갔다.
When I get back, I'll ask you to go to your house.
내가 돌아오면 당신 집으로 가라고 할게요.
here
여기
I'll wait until you come
당신이 올 때까지 기다릴게요
I know who the serial killer is
연쇄살인범이 누군지 알아요
Your butler Jang Gye-jo
너의 집사 장계조
From the fortune telling teacher
운세 선생님으로부터
Items not received
상품을 받지 못함
I got it
알겠어요
How much will it cost?
비용은 얼마나 들까요?
It's priceless.
그것은 매우 귀중합니다.
If I tell you who that person is
그 사람이 누구인지 말하면
you just
방금
Please kill him instead.
대신 그를 죽여주세요.
If so, do you know who the culprit is?
그렇다면 범인이 누구인지 아시나요?
Do you remember the six disadvantages?
6가지 단점을 기억하시나요?
Six poor?
가난한 여섯 명?
Pyeong-a
평아
Brother, be careful.
형님, 조심하세요.
young master
젊은 주인
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
be careful
조심하세요
ruler
자
Pyeong-ya, don’t cry.
평야야, 울지 마.
My brother has already sent the bird home.
내 동생은 이미 새를 집으로 보냈습니다.
You wanted the bird to go home, right?
새가 집에 가기를 바랐죠?
Has the bird come home?
새가 집에 왔나요?
Pyeong-ya, there’s nothing to be afraid of.
평야, 두려울 건 없어.
Look at this
이거 봐요
My brother had me lay down straw in advance.
형은 미리 짚을 깔아두라고 했어요.
It's fluffy
푹신푹신해요
It doesn't hurt at all
전혀 아프지 않아요
Come on, it's plain.
자, 간단합니다.
Haven’t we been here for a long time?
우리 여기에 온 지 꽤 오래되지 않았나요?
It's been a while
오랜만이야
The second oldest person who came to your house
집에 찾아온 두 번째로 나이 많은 사람
I used to go to Chuhwaru often.
저는 추화루에 자주 가곤 했어요.
He is bright
그는 밝다
Our noble family and personality
우리의 고귀한 가족과 개성
It's the complete opposite
완전 반대네요
let's go now
이제 가자
Don't get caught
잡히지 마세요
why?
왜?
Those kids
그 아이들
They are all students who go to a private school to study writing.
그들은 모두 글쓰기를 공부하기 위해 사립학교에 다니는 학생들이다.
That kid in front
앞에 있는 저 아이
He is the son of the silk store vice president and chairman.
그는 실크 가게 부사장이자 회장의 아들입니다.
When you call a gisaeng to your house every day and invite guests
매일 기생을 집으로 불러 손님을 초대할 때
When I go to call a gisaeng
기생 부르러 갈 때
I got hit once then
그때 한 번 당했어요
So it's better not to run into each other
그러니까 서로 마주치지 않는 게 좋을 거야
let's go
갑시다
I will kill everyone, leaving no one behind.
나는 한 사람도 남기지 않고 모두를 죽일 것이다.
boom
팔
The kids are here
아이들이 여기 있어요
This is the declaration of war you gave me.
이것이 당신이 나에게 준 선전포고문입니다.
I took General Dongdu with me
나는 동두장군을 데리고 갔다
I'm here to fight
나는 싸우기 위해 여기 있다
Isn’t that kid your master?
그 아이는 당신의 주인이 아닌가요?
that's right
좋아요
boom
팔
All four generals were bitten and died.
네 명의 장군이 모두 물려 죽었습니다.
Do you have any more competitions?
대회가 더 있나요?
The person next to you, Mr.
옆에 계신 분, Mr.
I think the second master of the grain store is evil.
내 생각엔 곡물 창고의 두 번째 주인이 악한 사람인 것 같아요.
Yukbulwu, evil road
육불우, 악의 길
Don't be puffed up
우쭐대지 마세요
I recently took on a warrior again.
나는 최근에 다시 전사를 맡았습니다.
Wonpae, Woo Moon Seong-do, Bae Won-kyung
원패, 우문성도, 배원경
These are all kids under me.
다 내 밑에 있는 애들이야
So it doesn’t matter whether you are Dongdu or Cheoldu.
그러니 당신이 동두인지 철두인지는 중요하지 않습니다.
It's nothing to me
나에겐 아무것도 아니야
I was surprised
놀랐습니다
you shut your mouth
너 입 다물어
They say it well
그 사람들 말은 잘 하던데
Are we going to play cricket later?
나중에 크리켓 경기를 할 건가요?
Or are you competing?
아니면 경쟁하고 있나요?
There are so many useless words
쓸데없는 말이 너무 많아
Let's get started quickly
빨리 시작해보자
- ask
- 물어보세요
Don't stay there, keep asking
거기 머물지 말고 계속 물어보세요
bite
깨물다
I can't stand it
나는 그것을 참을 수 없다
I'll come see Sophie.
소피를 만나러 갈게요.
Kill General Dongdu
동두 장군을 죽여라
General Dongdu
동두장군
- Ask quickly - Ask
- 빨리 물어보세요 - 물어보세요
- General Dongdu
- 묻다 - 동두장군
Ask quickly
빨리 물어보세요
cheer up
기운을 내다
- ask
- 물어보세요
bite and kill
물고 죽여라
Where did you get this chicken?
이 치킨은 어디서 구하셨나요?
my cricket
내 귀뚜라미
became food for chickens
닭의 먹이가 되다
the chicken didn't eat
치킨은 안 먹었어
General Dongdu
동두장군
was here
여기 있었다
What should I do because I’m sorry?
미안하니까 어떻게 해야 하나요?
I accidentally stepped on it
실수로 밟았어
Are you angry?
화가 났나요?
Why are you so angry?
왜 그렇게 화가 났어?
I'll show you
내가 보여줄게
How strong is General Dongdu’s head?
동두 장군의 머리는 얼마나 강합니까?
Kneel down
에 무릎을 꿇고 앉다
Give me strength
나에게 힘을 줘
press
누르다
work hard
열심히 일하다
Janggwi, Jinwang
장귀, 진왕
Wang Oyuk, Yui
왕오육, 유이
Come quickly
빨리 오세요
Your family's master is being bullied.
당신 가족의 주인이 괴롭힘을 당하고 있습니다.
hurry
서두르다
six jobs
여섯 가지 직업
Who did you just call?
방금 누구한테 전화했어요?
I called my servant
나는 내 하인에게 전화를 걸었다.
It's around here, we'll be there soon.
이 근처에 있어요. 곧 도착할 거예요.
okay
좋아요
If not, let's wait
그렇지 않다면 기다리자
Who are these two people?
이 두 사람은 누구입니까?
One is our servant
한 명은 우리 하인이에요
one person
한 사람
I do not know either
나도 모른다
It seems like everyone has forgotten about you.
모두가 당신을 잊어버린 것 같습니다.
I'll find you a cool place, so wait there.
내가 좋은 곳을 찾아줄 테니 거기서 기다리세요.
Beat me to death
나를 때려죽이게 하라
Opportunities like this are rare.
이런 기회는 흔치 않습니다.
You didn't beat him to death, right?
당신이 그 사람을 때려죽인 건 아니죠?
Because I’m thirsty
목이 마르니까
I was drinking water
나는 물을 마시고 있었다
I'm glad you didn't hurt your eyes.
눈은 안 다치셨다니 다행이네요.
My face is ruined
얼굴이 망가졌어
Eyebrows represent brothers.
눈썹은 형제를 상징합니다.
I saw it in a physiognomy book
생리학 책에서 봤어
Acquired loss of eyebrows
눈썹 상실
They say brothers become enemies
형제가 적이 된다고 하던데
I'll go and ask if there is a solution.
가서 해결책이 있는지 물어보겠습니다.
The grain store owner
곡물가게 주인
Do you know how to look at physiognomy?
관상학을 보는 방법을 알고 있습니까?
There is a fortune telling teacher next to my store.
내 가게 옆에는 점술사님이 계십니다.
Sometimes I steal rice
가끔 밥을 훔쳐먹기도 해요
I gave it to the fortune telling teacher.
운세 선생님께 드렸습니다.
They ask me to teach them a trick.
그들은 나에게 트릭을 가르쳐달라고 요청합니다.
You asked me to teach you a trick?
나한테 비법을 가르쳐달라고 했나?
If that person is talented
그 사람이 재능이 있다면
Was it necessary for you to steal rice?
쌀을 훔칠 필요가 있었나요?
When I see it
내가 볼 때
That fortune telling teacher seems to have a talent.
그 점술 선생님은 재능이 있는 것 같아요.
The teacher
선생님
The grain store owner
곡물가게 주인
He knew that people would steal rice for him.
그는 사람들이 그를 위해 쌀을 훔칠 것이라는 것을 알고 있었습니다.
the slate
슬레이트
It must have been opened next to a grain store.
분명 곡물 가게 옆에 문을 열었을 거예요.
Thanks for your help
당신의 도움을 주셔서 감사합니다
What is your name?
이름이 뭐에요?
Me?
나?
They say it's a minor
미성년자라고 하던데
You are my friend
당신은 내 친구입니다
Who is your servant?
당신의 종이 누구입니까?
no
아니요
This is Chuwaru’s servant.
츄와루의 하인입니다.
Your servant
당신의 종
Why are you friends with a turtle?
거북이랑 왜 친구야?
What's wrong with the turtle?
거북이에게 무슨 문제가 있나요?
Just now this turtle hyung
지금 이 거북이 형
If you didn't help me
당신이 나를 도와주지 않았다면
You, the grain store master,
곡물 창고 주인이신 당신,
It probably turned into a piece of cake
아마 케이크 조각으로 변했을 거야
why?
왜?
Now it's wet and dead
지금은 젖어 죽었어
You don't admit it?
인정하지 않나요?
Rather stay at Chuhwaru.
차라리 추화루에 묵으세요.
Don't come to my room
내 방에 오지 마
It's unclean
불결하다
No, ma'am
아니요, 부인
This is all Joe Giant
이게 다 조 자이언트야
They dragged me in because they wanted to entertain me.
그들은 나를 즐겁게 해주고 싶어서 나를 끌고 갔습니다.
I just had a little drink.
방금 술을 조금 마셨어요.
second elder
둘째 장로
About me
나에 대해서
entertainment
오락
I think it can only be called entertainment if it feels like entertainment.
오락적인 느낌이 있어야만 오락이라고 할 수 있다고 생각합니다.
A passionate encounter is difficult to break up with
뜨거운 만남은 헤어지기 어렵다
They say it will be difficult to meet again if it cools down.
식어버리면 다시 만나기 힘들다고 하더라고요.
Look at this, it hasn't even gotten dark.
이것 좀 보세요, 아직 어두워지지도 않았네요.
If you come back so quickly
그렇게 빨리 돌아오면
Wouldn’t it ruin someone else’s excitement?
다른 사람의 흥분을 망치지 않을까요?
honey
꿀
Go back quickly
빨리 돌아가라
Enjoy it hot
뜨겁게 즐겨라
No, ma'am
아니요, 부인
ma'am
나는 가지고있다
six jobs
여섯 가지 직업
What are you holding like that?
뭘 그렇게 들고 있어?
This is the hangover soup that Sooksu made for the second elder.
숙수가 둘째 어르신을 위해 만들어준 해장국입니다 .
Now it's for my father
이제 아버지를 위한 것입니다.
I don't think it's necessary
나는 그것이 필요하다고 생각하지 않는다
My mother is already waking me up
엄마가 벌써 나를 깨우고 계세요
let's go
갑시다
Let's play in the backyard flower garden
뒷마당 꽃밭에서 놀자
Don't interfere with your father sobering up.
아버지가 술을 깨시는 걸 방해하지 마세요.
No, where are you going?
아니, 어디로 가는 거야?
Are you going to leave me here alone?
나를 여기에 혼자 남겨두실 건가요?
What's wrong with being alone?
혼자 있는 게 뭐가 문제야?
Let's do it this way
이렇게 하자
I
나
Let me test how you studied today.
오늘 공부를 어떻게 했는지 테스트해 보겠습니다.
What did you learn at Seodang today?
오늘 서당에서 무엇을 배웠나요?
today
오늘
I learned ‘Analects of Confucius’
'논어'를 배웠어요
Confucius said
공자께서 말씀하셨다.
Lee Eui-ho!
이의호!
Omigyeonhodeok is a lecherous woman
오미견호덕은 음란한 여자야
father
아버지
What does this mean?
이것은 무엇을 의미 하는가?
Didn’t the teacher teach you?
선생님이 가르쳐주지 않았나요?
You told me
당신은 나에게 말했다
What this means is...
이것이 의미하는 바는...
Confucius said
공자께서 말씀하셨다.
It's the end.
이제 끝이다.
I'm a person who likes colors
나는 색깔을 좋아하는 사람이다.
I have never seen anyone who likes virtue.
나는 덕을 좋아하는 사람을 본 적이 없습니다.
father
아버지
Is there anything else you can teach me?
나에게 또 가르쳐 줄 것이 있나요?
Your teacher's interpretation is correct.
선생님의 해석이 맞습니다.
I have nothing more to teach you
나는 너에게 더 이상 가르칠 것이 없다.
father
아버지
Omigyeonhodeok is a lecherous woman
오미견호덕은 음란한 여자야
This passage is from the ‘Analects of Confucius’
이 구절은 '논어(論論)'에서 따온 것이다.
It didn't happen once or twice
그런 일이 한두 번도 아니었어.
In addition to ‘Memorial Flight’
'기념비행' 외에도
It also appeared in ‘Jahanpyeon’
'자한편'에도 출연했다.
What is the reason?
이유는 무엇입니까?
Maybe this verse
아마도 이 구절은
In ‘Analects of Confucius’
'공자 논어'에서
Is it the most important phrase?
가장 중요한 문구인가요?
Poor guy
가난한 사람
Have you already learned something this profound?
이미 이렇게 심오한 것을 배웠나요?
He said he would test my son.
그는 내 아들을 시험하겠다고 말했습니다.
Instead, you got hit?
대신에 맞았어?
A person named Sujae
이름이 수재인 사람
Don't lose face in front of your son.
아들 앞에서 체면을 잃지 마십시오.
I was with my butler before.
예전에 집사랑 같이 있었거든요.
How did you come alone today?
오늘은 어떻게 혼자 오셨나요?
Chungya went to the field to do some work.
청야는 일을 하러 밭에 나갔습니다.
You and Chungya
너와 청야
I saw you fishing here
여기서 낚시하는 걸 봤어
I thought it was easy to catch
잡기 쉬울줄 알았는데
I came fishing a few times.
낚시하러 몇 번 왔어요.
The results are always dismal.
결과는 늘 참담하다.
The fish here are
여기 물고기는
Smarter than the ones at home
집에 있는 것보다 더 똑똑해
You're just hiding your face.
당신은 단지 당신의 얼굴을 숨기고 있습니다.
All adults say that.
어른들은 다 그렇게 말해요.
People naturally become friends
사람들은 자연스럽게 친구가 된다
But I don’t think it’s a fish
하지만 물고기는 아닌 것 같아요
Yukjikah
어서 해봐요
Your last name wasn't Yuk from the beginning, right?
성은 처음부터 육(Yuk)이 아니었지요?
I am a beggar who was picked up by the Yuk family.
나는 육씨 가문에 픽업된 거지입니다.
So I followed the Yuk family’s last name.
그래서 육가의 성을 따랐습니다.
I think
제 생각에는
My uncle picked it up for me too.
삼촌도 나를 위해 그것을 골라 주셨습니다.
I feel like I've become a master
마치 마스터가 된 것 같은 기분이에요
If I say this
내가 이렇게 말하면
Do you want to look like you don't care about other people's circumstances ?
다른 사람의 상황에 관심이 없는 것처럼 보이고 싶나요 ?
Because everyone has a destiny
누구에게나 운명이 있으니까
What is your original last name?
원래 성은 무엇입니까?
Mr. Seol
설씨
How old are you?
몇 살이에요?
It's the year of the horse
말의 해다
What month are you born in?
당신은 몇 월에 태어났나요?
It's April
4월이에요
Well, he was born two months earlier than me.
글쎄요, 그 사람은 나보다 두 달 일찍 태어났어요.
Brother Seol
설 형제
Greetings from Yukbulwoo
육불우에서 인사드립니다.
Rep. Jeong
정 의원
After quitting about two coats
2회 정도 끊은 후
Yuk Won-bok's health is recovering again.
육원복 씨의 건강이 다시 회복되고 있습니다.
Killing six atomic bombs won't do us any good.
여섯 개의 원자폭탄을 죽이는 것은 우리에게 아무 소용이 없습니다.
Do you want to give up?
포기하고 싶나요?
Chungya
청야
Second, after the elder’s family came here
둘째, 장로님 가족이 이곳에 오신 후
Our plans have been postponed
우리 계획은 연기됐어
But I felt rather relieved.
하지만 오히려 마음이 편해졌습니다.
Chungya
청야
I can sleep comfortably now
이제 편히 잠들 수 있겠네요
before we
우리 전에
With Mr. Wang
왕 선생님과 함께
If you think back on what you said to Rep. Jeong,
정 의원에게 했던 말을 돌이켜보면,
It's like a dream
꿈같아
I now
나 지금
I think it's off
내 생각엔 꺼진 것 같아
can't escape
탈출할 수 없어
you can't escape forever
넌 영원히 벗어날 수 없어
For life?
평생?
If we don't implement this plan
우리가 이 계획을 실행하지 않으면
until I die
내가 죽을 때까지
I have to live dumb
멍청하게 살아야 해
until you die
당신이 죽을 때까지
I have to live as a slave in this house.
나는 이 집에서 노예로 살아야 한다.
Chungya
청야
I'm not sure
잘 모르겠어요
What should I do next?
다음에 무엇을 해야 합니까?
I don't know if I should continue
계속해야 할지 모르겠어요
Yukjikah
어서 해봐요
That's what Bulwoo said to me.
불우가 나에게 그렇게 말했다.
I want to make you my sister-in-law
당신을 형수로 삼고 싶어요
You and the unfortunate are also meant to be
당신과 불행한 사람도 운명이 되어 있어요
Since you have studied writing before,
예전에 글쓰기를 공부한 적이 있어서,
I talked to my brother.
나는 동생과 이야기를 나눴다.
Second child
둘째 아이
This kid was my litter
이 아이는 내 쓰레기였어
But I'm not satisfied with Baedong.
하지만 나는 배동에 만족하지 않는다.
How could you insist on having me as your father ?
어떻게 나를 아버지로 삼을 수 있겠습니까?
To be honest
솔직히 말하자면
Joe The Giant likes you.
조 더 자이언트가 당신을 좋아합니다.
to me many times
나한테 여러번
They say they want to buy you out
그들은 당신을 매수하고 싶다고 말해요
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
That giant giant
그 거대한 거인
It would be easier to fool than me.
나보다 속이는 것이 더 쉬울 것입니다.
If you make Giant Joe feel good
자이언트 조의 기분을 좋게 만들어준다면
Couldn't I say I will make you my son?
내가 너를 내 아들로 삼겠다고 말할 수는 없었느냐?
Yukjikah
어서 해봐요
Do you want to be Bae Dong?
배동이 되고 싶니?
Or do you want to follow Joe Giant?
아니면 조 자이언트(Joe Giant)를 따르고 싶나요?
I will donate
기부하겠습니다
If you do the distribution
배포를 하면
Wouldn’t it be unfair?
불공평하지 않을까요?
Yukjikah
어서 해봐요
There's nothing to worry about
걱정할 건 없어
Because you are intelligent and clever
당신은 똑똑하고 영리하기 때문에
To be loyal to our Yuk family
Yuk 가족에게 충실하기 위해
I know
알아요
I'm good at persuading my brother
나는 동생을 잘 설득한다.
Don't let me sell you to Giant Joe.
당신을 자이언트 조에게 팔지 마세요.
If you do your best
최선을 다하면
You too will become the owner later
너도 나중에 주인이 될 거야
You can become a butler
집사가 될 수 있어요
If you don't have any other thoughts
다른 생각이 없다면
my family
나의 가족
I will keep you by my side and serve us for the rest of my life.
나는 당신을 내 곁에 두고 평생 동안 우리를 섬길 것입니다.
Are you saying you'll take care of it for life?
평생 책임진다고 하던데요?
Second child
둘째 아이
Only you have become a good person
너만 좋은 사람이 됐어
Okay, I'll do as you say.
알았어, 네 말대로 할게.
Yukjikah
어서 해봐요
Stay and become the master's companion.
머물면서 주인의 동반자가 되십시오.
I won't let the giant give up
거인이 포기하도록 놔두지 않을 거야
What are you looking at?
무엇을 보고 있나요?
Don't thank the second elder
둘째 장로에게 감사하지 말라
Second Elder, thank you
둘째 장로님, 감사합니다
Thanks to the second adult today
오늘은 두 번째 어른 덕분에
I knew what to do
나는 무엇을 해야할지 알고 있었다
I'm moving forward
나는 앞으로 나아간다
I will do anything for the sake of the Yuk family.
육가족을 위해서라면 뭐든지 하겠습니다.
I'll do my best
난 최선을 다 할거야
Rep. Jeong
정 의원
Please add a little more medicine.
약을 조금 더 추가해주세요.
What medicine do you mean?
무슨 약이라니?
A drug that can kill a person
사람을 죽일 수도 있는 약
Are you out of your mind?
당신 미쳤어?
The medicine I gave you is also effective.
내가 준 약도 효과가 있어요.
Just a little slow
조금 느릴 뿐이야
But if you suddenly ask me to use strong medicine,
그런데 갑자기 독한 약을 쓰라고 하면
Isn’t there a gift left?
선물이 남지 않았나요?
Even if the gift remains, it won’t be detrimental to Rep. Jeong.
선물이 남아도 정 의원에게 손해가 되지는 않는다.
Rep. Jeong
정 의원
It doesn't matter if you don't give me medicine.
약을 안 줘도 상관없어요.
To me
나에게
There is arsenic that can even kill rats.
쥐도 죽일 수 있는 비소가 있습니다.
If it doesn't work out
문제가 해결되지 않으면
You can just put it in the medicine that Rep. Jeong gave you.
정 의원이 드린 약에 그냥 넣으시면 됩니다.
Okay, I'll do it.
알았어, 내가 할게.
Big brother
형
(Memorial tablet of the six atomic bombs of my brother)
(동생의 6개 원자폭탄 위패)
The love between our brothers
우리 형제간의 사랑
It's so short
너무 짧다
How did you end up here?
어떻게 여기까지 왔나요?
Big brother
형
(A favor received will always be repaid)
(받은 은혜는 반드시 갚는다)
young master
젊은 주인
The six atomic bombs have already been dealt with.
6개의 원자폭탄은 이미 처리되었습니다.
Who will we deal with next?
다음에는 누구를 상대할까요?
Let's wait a moment
잠시만 기다리자
Let's wait about three months.
3개월 정도 기다려보자.
Sooksu
숙수
Master, please sit down.
선생님, 자리에 앉으세요.
This duck meat is done right away.
이렇게 오리고기가 바로 완성됩니다.
It's delicious if you eat it while it's hot.
뜨거울 때 먹으면 맛있어요.
Sooksu
숙수
Isn’t it Suksoo’s birthday today?
오늘 석수 생일 아니었어?
How can I be the only one?
어떻게 내가 유일한 사람이 될 수 있나요?
I only called you Mr.
나는 단지 당신을 Mr.라고 불렀습니다.
Do you have something to tell me?
나한테 할 말 있어?
young master
젊은 주인
incident
사건
He committed it
그는 그것을 저질렀다
What did you say just now?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
That incident
그 사건
The case of poisoning an elderly person
노인을 중독시킨 사건
I committed it.
나는 그것을 저질렀다.
Sir, are you drunk?
선생님, 취하셨나요?
How can you say such a thing?
어떻게 그런 말을 할 수 있나요?
I have business to do
나는 할 일이 있어요
Let's go first
먼저 가자
Sit!
앉다!
young master
젊은 주인
think about it carefully
잘 생각해보세요
I'm on your side
난 네 편이야
Otherwise
그렇지 않으면
Call the master here
여기로 마스터를 불러주세요
There's no way you could say something like this, right?
이런 말을 할 리가 없잖아요?
Sooksu
숙수
What is the reason for this happening all of a sudden?
갑자기 이런 일이 일어나는 이유는 무엇입니까?
You know this, too, right?
너도 이거 알지?
I am
그래요
Janggwi, Jinwang and
장귀, 진왕 그리고
It's a drinking party
술파티다
Every few days we
우리는 며칠마다
We're drinking together
우리는 함께 술을 마시고 있어요
I drink enough to get drunk every time.
매번 취하게 될 정도로 술을 마신다.
As long as Jang Gui and King Jin get drunk,
장귀와 진왕이 술에 취한 한,
I keep talking.
나는 계속 말하고 있다.
between these two months
이 두 달 사이에
I roughly
나는 대충
I noticed it
나는 그것을 알아 차렸다
Of course, I said it when I was drunk.
물론 술에 취해서 한 말이다.
someday
언젠가
Who knows, maybe you'll even remember it?
어쩌면 당신이 그것을 기억할지도 누가 알겠습니까?
When that time comes
그 때가 오면
My life is in danger
내 생명이 위험해
I gave it some thought.
나는 그것에 대해 좀 생각해 보았다.
Then, rather than pretending not to know and hoping for a fluke,
그렇다면 모르는 척, 우연을 바라기보다는,
rather
꽤
I told the master openly
나는 주인에게 공개적으로 말했다.
If we hold hands
우리 손을 잡으면
I thought there might be good results.
좋은 결과가 있지 않을까 싶었습니다.
If not, report it to the government office.
그렇지 않은 경우 관공서에 신고하세요.
Second, report it to the elder.
둘째, 장로에게 보고하라.
Me?
나?
like me
나처럼
Are you staying overnight?
밤새 묵을 건가요?
What those two servants said while drunk
저 두 하인이 술에 취해 한 말
If you report this case as a murder case
이 사건을 살인사건으로 신고하면
Who will believe it?
누가 그것을 믿을 것인가?
Sooksu
숙수
I underestimated you, Master.
제가 당신을 과소평가했어요, 마스터.
Before, I just thought you were ignorant.
예전에는 당신이 무식한 줄로만 알았습니다.
The only person who was this careful
이렇게 조심했던 유일한 사람
I never even thought about it
난 그것에 대해 생각해본 적도 없어
young master
젊은 주인
You lift me up so much
당신은 나를 너무 기분 좋게 만들어 주네요
That's right, I'm ignorant.
그렇군요, 저는 무지합니다.
But even ignorant people have ideas.
그러나 무지한 사람이라도 생각은 있습니다.
Sooksu
숙수
I was rude
나는 무례했다
Sore
아픈
Master
주인
I don't know if you'll believe me
당신이 내 말을 믿을지 모르겠어요
I want to believe in you
나는 당신을 믿고 싶어
But with just a few words
하지만 몇 마디만으로
How can I believe it?
어떻게 믿을 수 있나요?
I understand everything too
나도 다 이해해
If so, let me tell you.
그렇다면 말씀드리겠습니다.
What should I do so that you will trust me?
당신이 나를 신뢰하게 하려면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Let's do this
이렇게 해보자
tomorrow morning
내일 아침
Under the firewood in the barn
헛간 장작 아래
find this bowl
이 그릇을 찾아라
under the bowl
그릇 아래
There must be a bag of medicine.
약봉지가 있어야 합니다.
Choose any of the servants
하인 중 하나를 선택하십시오
Put medicine in that person’s food.
그 사람의 음식에 약을 넣어보세요.
I say it openly
대놓고 말하는데
This is a poison that kills instantly if it enters the bloodstream.
이것은 혈류에 들어가면 즉시 죽이는 독입니다.
to me
나에게
There is a way to solve the problem on the government side.
정부 차원에서 문제를 해결하는 방법이 있다.
If you say he died of illness, that's enough.
그가 병으로 죽었다고 하면 그것으로 충분하다.
If only you could do it
당신이 할 수만 있다면
I'll believe you
나는 당신을 믿을 것이다
young master
젊은 주인
poisoning people
사람들을 중독시키다
What's so difficult?
뭐가 그렇게 어렵나요?
I will do it
내가 할게
I wonder who they will poison then?
그러면 그들이 누구를 독살할지 궁금합니다.
I'm Wang Oh-yuk, a chore worker.
잡일을 하는 왕오육 입니다.
I still haven't paid the money I owe him.
나는 아직도 그 사람에게 빚진 돈을 갚지 못했습니다.
Otherwise, I 'll be ready to collect the body .
그렇지 않으면 제가 시체를 수거할 준비가 되어 있을 것입니다.
No way?
안 돼요?
young master
젊은 주인
Sooksu
숙수
I...
나...
I really used that drug
나 정말 그 약을 썼어
And that's a considerable amount.
그리고 그것은 상당한 금액입니다.
All in one bag
가방 하나에 모두 담다
I put it in
나는 그것을 넣었다
I haven't seen Wang Oyuk all day.
나는 하루 종일 왕오육을 보지 못했다.
But he didn't die
하지만 그는 죽지 않았다
I was in and out of the back all day last night.
나는 어젯밤 하루 종일 뒤돌아서 있었다.
Today I just slept all day
오늘은 그냥 하루종일 잤어요
young master
젊은 주인
Isn't that medicine fake?
그 약은 가짜 아닌가요?
Maybe there is medicine
약이 있을지도 몰라
Isn't that ineffective?
효과가 없는 것 아닌가요?
It seems to be working?
효과가 있는 것 같나요?
What I gave to my master was a laxative.
내가 주인님께 드린 것은 완하제였습니다.
I'll believe you
나는 당신을 믿을 것이다
Sooksu
숙수
light it up
불을 켜다
No, you want to kill everyone?
아니, 다 죽이고 싶어?
young master
젊은 주인
Think about it again
다시 생각해 보세요
There's no need to kill them all, right?
다 죽일 필요는 없잖아요?
If you kill just four members of the Yuk family,
육가문 네명만 죽이면
Being...
존재...
furthermore
뿐만 아니라
so many people
너무 많은 사람들
Everyone has hands and feet
사람은 누구나 손과 발을 가지고 있다
How
어떻게
Do you keep them in one place?
한 곳에 보관하시나요?
It's obvious that at least one or two people will escape.
적어도 한두 명은 탈출할 게 뻔하다.
before starting the fire
불을 피우기 전에
What if I kill them all?
내가 그 사람들을 모두 죽이면 어쩌지?
But with so many servants
하지만 하인이 너무 많아서
The four members of the Yuk family
Yuk 가족의 네 구성원
me and death penalty
나와 사형
And even if we join forces until the middle of the night
그리고 우리가 한밤중까지 힘을 합쳐도
Killing them all at once
한꺼번에 다 죽여버려
As long as you don't make a fuss
당신이 소란을 피우지 않는 한
It is difficult
가 어렵다
Chungya
청야
Is there anything you are worried about?
걱정되는 것이 있나요?
(It's hard to kill them all)
(모두 죽이는 것은 어렵습니다)
(Postprocessing is more difficult)
(후처리가 더 어렵습니다)
Chungya’s words are
청야의 말은
My whole family died in a fire.
우리 가족 모두가 화재로 사망했습니다.
If the servant who fortunately survives takes all the property,
다행히 살아남은 종이 재산을 모두 가져가면,
It's obvious that I'll be suspicious
의심할 게 분명해
Even if there is a will
의지가 있어도
The government does not believe it
정부는 그것을 믿지 않는다
Are you saying they're going to interrogate me because they think I killed my owner and stole his property ?
내가 주인을 죽이고 그의 재산을 훔쳤다고 생각해서 나를 심문하겠다는 겁니까?
I also know a bit about government affairs.
나는 또한 정부 업무에 대해서도 조금 알고 있습니다.
The time has come
때가 왔다
When the sentence is handed down
형이 선고될 때
I will also tell the truth about everything.
나는 또한 모든 것에 대해 진실을 말할 것입니다.
ruler
자
There's nothing to worry about
걱정할 건 없어
That's actually easier to solve
실제로 해결하기가 더 쉽습니다.
The difficult thing now
지금 어려운 건
Those people
저 사람들
Let them burn to death in one place.
한곳에서 불타 죽게 놔두세요.
It's not that difficult either
그리 어렵지도 않아요
This is datura powder
다추라가루 입니다
Datura of Yeongnam
영남의 다투라
It's not a rare flower either.
흔한 꽃도 아닙니다.
This is made from datura
이건 다투라로 만든거야
Anesthetic?
마취제?
Just eating makes me fall asleep
먹기만 해도 잠이 든다
How many people can you take down with this one bottle?
이 한 병으로 몇 명이나 쓰러뜨릴 수 있나요?
It's enough to knock down a couple of guys
두 명을 쓰러뜨리기에 충분합니다.
If so, isn't the difference too big?
그렇다면 차이가 너무 크지 않은가?
I know where you can make this.
나는 당신이 이것을 어디서 만들 수 있는지 알고 있습니다.
Is this amount okay?
이 금액 괜찮나요?
I can taste it too
나도 맛볼 수 있어
If you put this in your food, you could get caught.
이것을 음식에 넣으면 잡힐 수 있습니다.
If you don't stir it properly
제대로 저어주지 않으면
And the amount will not be enough
그리고 금액이 충분하지 않을 것입니다
I usually put it in alcohol.
보통은 술에 타서 먹거든요.
Or I'll make Palbochantang (palbochantang)
아니면 팔보찬탕 만들게요
The soup contains alcohol and sheep fat.
수프에는 알코올과 양 지방이 포함되어 있습니다.
Chives are also added
부추도 추가됩니다
It will cover the taste.
맛이 가려지네요.
Put the medicine in the bath
욕조에 약을 넣고
Season the food a little salty
음식에 약간 짠맛을 더해주세요
Just feed it a lot.
그냥 많이 먹이세요.
From the looks of it, this isn't difficult.
겉으로 보기에는 어렵지 않습니다.
If you are truly six poor
당신이 정말로 여섯 명의 가난한 사람이라면
Where is that person now?
그 사람은 지금 어디에 있나요?
It's in the government office.
정부청사에 있어요.
This is a bad smell
이건 나쁜 냄새야
This is a note hidden in the donkey’s body.
당나귀 몸 속에 숨겨져 있던 쪽지입니다.
20 years have passed
20년이 지났다
The culprit is probably
범인은 아마도
You must have been thinking about how to get revenge.
어떻게 하면 복수할 수 있을지 고민하고 계셨을 텐데요.
Moreover, the snow giant
게다가 눈의 거인
already
이미
That he has become a rich and powerful giant
그는 부유하고 강력한 거인이 되었다고
my teacher
선생님
You probably know that I helped the Seol Giant get rid of Jeungjwa .
내가 설거인이 증좌를 없애는 데 도움을 준 건 아마 당신도 알고 있을 것이다.
So
그래서
the most direct and
가장 직접적이고
You must have used a refreshing method.
상쾌한 방법을 사용하셨나 봐요.
(The above prefectural ordinance is six fires)
(위의 현 조례는 6 건의 화재입니다)
The above prefecture?
위의 현?
The above prefecture is said to be six poor people?
위 현은 가난한 사람이 6명이라고 하네요?
(Prison Grade)
(교도소급)
♪The center of the bone and the edge of the blade♪
♪뼈의 중심과 칼날의 가장자리♪
♪It’s sweet yet sticky♪
♪달콤하면서도 쫄깃쫄깃해요♪
♪If you bite into something new and drink something old♪
♪새로운 것을 먹고, 오래된 것을 마시면♪
♪Some cry, some sleep♪
♪누구는 울고, 누구는 자고♪
♪We will honor the sacrifice with a full table♪
♪희생을 기리며 만찬을 차리겠습니다♪
♪Only the barren hills are visible♪
♪불모의 언덕만이 보입니다♪
♪ To the old road and clear, green, bustling city in the distance ♪
♪ 오래된 길과 저 멀리 맑고 푸르고 번화한 도시로 ♪
♪Because the fire continues, it is turning into ruins♪
♪불이 계속되서 폐허가 되어가고 있어요♪
♪The fateful prize that will feed you well♪
♪배불리 먹여줄 운명의 상품♪
♪He looks at the fortune telling and says thank you♪
♪운세를 보고 고맙다고 인사해요♪
♪The false accusations written in the drunken oath and the appeal♪
♪술취한 맹세에 적힌 거짓 고발과 항소♪
♪When the wind blows, it disappears♪
♪바람이 불면 사라져요♪
♪We will honor the sacrifice with a full table♪
♪희생을 기리며 만찬을 차리겠습니다♪
♪Only the barren hills are visible♪
♪불모의 언덕만이 보입니다♪
♪ To the old road and clear, green, bustling city in the distance ♪
♪ 오래된 길과 저 멀리 맑고 푸르고 번화한 도시로 ♪
♪Because the fire continues, it is turning into ruins♪
♪불이 계속되서 폐허가 되어가고 있어요♪